#### Mail

kartikgt23@gmail.com

#### **Contact**

(+91) 9800131277

#### Website

kartikgt.github.io

#### **Focus Areas**

- Machine Learning
- Distributed Computing
- Big Data Engineering
- Data Science
- Cloud Integration
- Monitoring Tools
- Automation
- Product Management
- Technical Writing

#### **Competencies**

- o Python, Java, SQL
- Hadoop, Hive, Spark
- Tensorflow and Keras
- o NumPy, Pandas, SciPy
- o Requests, BS4
- Microsoft Azure
- Selenium, Webdriver
- o Elasticsearch, Kibana
- o Splunk, Zabbix
- o Jenkins, Git, Ansible
- o InfluxDB, Grafana

#### **Hobbies**

I am a publisher at Substack where I write about technology and its impact. Keeping upto date with thought leaders and technology experts on twitter and reading books is how i spend my time. I relish public speaking opportunities and have participated in debate competitions and university elections. An avid follower of sports in general, I play football and swim.

# **Kartik Gupta**

# **Experience**

## Jun 2018 - present, Associate Developer, SAP Labs

- Designed and developed the end-to-end infrastructure for efficient, scalable, and secure data integration across all cloud applications.
- Implemented a data lake in Hadoop to process application metrics, and load transformed data into data warehouse (ELK) for analysis.
- Automated the entire pipeline in compliance with Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery practices (Git and Jenkins).
- Developed machine learning models utilizing regression and time series analysis for anomaly detection, alerting, and traffic prediction.
- Automated the functional testing of web applications with Selenium Webdriver, and python scripts for generating monitoring reports.
- Wrote Ansible cookbooks to configure and deploy Splunk application.
- Indexed application data into Splunk and designed dashboards and visualizations for interactive and expressive monitoring requirements.
- Performed on-call duties and attended bridge calls to resolve P1 application issues alongwith ticket management (JIRA and ServiceNow).

## May 2017 - Jul 2017, Summer Intern, Nomura Research Institute

- Executed a data governance project for the compliance of a broker back office data ecosystem with the data privacy GDPR guidelines.
- Developed solutions for ensuring data integrity, encryption of PIIs, and data mapping by identifying lineages in 50,000+ schemas.

## May 2016 - Jul 2016, Summer Intern, Miebach Consulting

- Identified key Indian ports and industries for introduction of cold storage, CFS and ICDs to support existing supply chain systems.
- Formulated an Auto Replenishment System for a retail client to ensure constant stock availability and capacity prediction.

# **Education**

# 2013 - 2018, Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur

Integrated Dual Degree, Electronics and Electrical Engineering

- CGPA: 7.47 / 10
- Masters' Thesis Project: Translating Images to Natural Language Sentences using Deep Neural Networks for Captioning.
- Bachelors' Thesis Project: Blur kernel estimation in images using a softmax criterion with a Convolutional Neural Network.

## Extra-Curricular

## April 2014 - May 2018, Spring Fest, cultural fest of IIT Kharagpur

- *Steering Committee Member*, Advised and mentored a team of 50+ students responsible for organizing and conducting the fest.
- *Events Head*, Responsible for conceptualizing, planning, and executing the events held during the 59th edition. Led a team of 25+ students and formed partnerships with 10+ associations worth INR 1 million.

# **Certifications and Courses**

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (Scheduled in June)
- Tensorflow 2.0: Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence Udemy
- Vue JS 2 The Complete Guide (incl. Vue Router and Vuex) Udemy